<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Greetings from Cyberspace!</title>
        <link>https://johnpearsall.com/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Greetings from Cyberspace!</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 15:19:26 -0600</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://johnpearsall.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>🖥️ Gateway to Adulthood</title>
            <link>https://johnpearsall.com/posts/ff-gateway-to-adulthood/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 15:19:26 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://johnpearsall.com/posts/ff-gateway-to-adulthood/</guid>
            <description>Introduction The year was 1999 and the new millennium, full of promises and bluster, was quickly approaching. I was offered a most generous choice for my graduation. The choice of graduation gift was a car or a computer. Much to my family&amp;rsquo;s chagrin, I chose the computer. Thus began a great ocean of time spent on IRC, Usenet, online games - specifically MUDs and Ultima Online, and the young &amp;ldquo;world-wide web&amp;rdquo; just entering a clumsy adolescence.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>The year was 1999 and the new millennium, full of promises and bluster, was
quickly approaching. I was offered a most generous choice for my graduation.
The choice of graduation gift was a car or a computer. Much to my family&rsquo;s
chagrin, I chose the computer. Thus began a great ocean of time spent on IRC,
Usenet, online games - specifically MUDs and Ultima Online, and the young
&ldquo;world-wide web&rdquo; just entering a clumsy adolescence. Our journey would be
taken together. Here is but a humble homage to those halcyon days.</p>
<h2 id="the-hardware">The Hardware</h2>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Component</th>
<th>Description</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>CPU</td>
<td>Pentium III 450MHz</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Memory</td>
<td>64MB</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Storage</td>
<td>10GB</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2D/3D Graphics</td>
<td>Voodoo 3 3000 AGP w/ 64MB video RAM</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Audio</td>
<td>Creative Sound Blaster 16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Communications</td>
<td>56K modem</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="does-it-boot">Does it Boot?</h2>
<p>After taking a moment to check the nearly 25 year-old capacitors, the moment
of truth has arrived. I press the power button feeling the <em>smoosh</em> of
nostalgia. I am welcomed by the BIOS splash screen and the memory test. Alas,
the familiar light blue screen with a boisterous &ldquo;Windows 98&rdquo; boot screen. A
good start! The rapid staccato of chucka-chucka-chucka as the hard drive head
sweeps across a magnetized platter. A most welcome chime resounds splendidly
over my thrifted speakers. We have boot!</p>
<h2 id="game-on">Game On!</h2>
<p>I hit the realization that I cannot engage in a time-honored tradition. There
is a game that has been ported to everything from toasters to refridgerators,
that would be id Software&rsquo;s brilliant contribution aptly named DOOM. However,
I did have my venerable copies of Quake and Duke Nukem 3D. I press the CD-ROM
eject button with much aplomb. <em>Rrr rrr chonk</em>. Well that didn&rsquo;t go splendidly.
I dig through my trove of thrifted goods and find a 52x drive and install it.
Hoo boy, FPSes sure have evolved since then. After fumbling around and dying
horribly with a huge grin on my face I decide to move onto the next step. That
being getting this thing online!</p>
<h2 id="nostalgia-online">Nostalgia Online?</h2>
<p>I grab the wifi modem that I use with my Apple <em>II</em>e and attach it to the rat
nest of serial cables, serial gender changers, and adapters. I try to dust off
the dusty corner of my brain that holds DB9/DB25 pinouts and the nuances of
DCE/DTE connections. After a couple of hours I&rsquo;m no closer to success. I&rsquo;m a
bit too engaged to want to break out the oscilloscope so I wait a couple days
for a compatible PCI wifi card to arrive. There is no native support for wifi
in Windows 98 Second Edition so I have to use the native software. This means,
for sake of convenience, using an insecure network. I do this over my phone as
I live in a secluded area and it is for a brief period of time. Sorry fellow
infosec engineers! It works! I immediately dial into the
<a href="https://bbs.fozztexx.com/">Level 29</a> and <a href="http://20forbeers.com:1339/">20ForBeers</a>
BBS. I lose the rest of the evening to catching up on messages and sneaking
time into Legend of the Red Dragon and TradeWars 2002.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>While I didn&rsquo;t meet all my goals, I&rsquo;ve definitely found room for improvement.
I already have a list of hardware upgrades and haven&rsquo;t given up hope on the
task of dial-up networking. Worst case, I&rsquo;ll dust off my RpISP and my phone
line simulator and get it going via dial-up. My nostalgia itch has been
scratched and I have a new toy to play with for my retro Fridays here-to now
referred to as fRetro Friday.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
